In this section, we'll learn a different kernel called
在这部分 我们将学习一个不同的核函数
the RBF or radial basis functions kernel.
即 RBF 或径向基核函数
So again, we have our points that we want to separate, and again,
和之前一样 我们要分离这些点
there is an old line that will separate them. So here's an idea.
同样地没有一条直线可以做到这点 办法就是
Let's draw this little mountain range over here which is pretty conveniently drawn.
在这里画一个小山脉 这很容易
Now, let's move every point to
现在 我们把每个点转移到
its corresponding point in the mountain range. And what a coincidence.
山脉上与之对应的点上 巧的是
The red points end up in highlands,
红点都在山顶位置
whereas the blue points end up in the valleys.
而蓝点都在山谷位置
And now, we're again in a two dimensional land,
现在 我们回到了一个二维空间里
and the points are separable.
这些点又可以分开了
Here's a line that will cut them.
这条线就可以分开它们
And what we do is we look at where the line intersects the mountain range,
我们要做的是 注意观察这条线和山脉的交点
we project everything down to the original line and now, we have our boundaries.
再把所有东西还原到原来的线上 就得到了分界线
They're given by these vertical cuts.
它们就是由这些垂线切割出来的
Magic. Now, that mountain range was a bit suspicious, a little too convenient.
很神奇 现在这座山脉好像有点太简单了 不太可信
The question is, how do we build a mountain range that will tend to locate
但问题在于 我们如何构建一座山脉
the red points in highlands and the blue points in lowlands? Well, here's a technique.
使红点位于山顶 蓝点位于山谷 技巧就在这里
Let's actually below a mountain on top of every point.
我们不妨在每个点上画一座山
The technical term for these mountings is radial basis functions,
这些山用术语来说就是径向基函数
and we'll see their formulas later.
稍后我们来看它们的公式
So, we built some functions that looked like this,
我们建立了一些这样的函数
and now, let's consider combining these functions.
然后把这些函数合并
How would we do it to build a range that helps us separate the blue and the red points?
如何建立一座山脉来把蓝点和红点分开呢？
Here's an idea. Let's flip the middle one,
办法就是 翻转中间的那个
or multiply it by minus one, and now,
或者将它乘以 -1 现在
add the three of them, and by adding,
把它们三个加起来
I literally mean the way you add functions,
我说的加起来就是把函数相加
so at every point, just add the three heights.
也就是把每一个点上的三个数值相加
If we add them, we get the following function.
那么我们就得出以下函数
And now, we move the points up or down to the corresponding point in the mountain range.
现在 我们将这些点往上或往下移到山脉上对应的位置
After we do this, now we can easily draw a line that splits the points in two.
然后 我们可以很容易地画出一条线 将这些点分成两部分
We proceed to draw this line.
我们继续绘制这条线
Let's say at height 0.5.
假设它的高度为 0.5
This line will intersect the mountain range at these points.
这条线将会与山脉相交于这些点
So, when we project down to the line,
那么 我们将点往下移到这条线上
we get these cuts over here which are our model.
就得到了分割线 也就是我们的模型
Notice that these cuts separate the blue points from the red points as we wanted.
这些分割线正好将蓝点和红点分开 达到了我们的目的
Now, we can go even farther.
我们可以进一步探究
Before, we just added and subtracted these functions, but now,
之前 我们只是在做加和减 但现在
we can actually multiply them by any constants that we want.
我们可以用它乘以任何我们想要的常量
We can do, for example,
比如 我们可以这样做
two times this one minus four times this one plus one times this one,
两倍的这个减去四倍的这个再加上一倍的这个
and let's say the sum is this.
假设它们的和是这个
And the line that cuts this is at height minus one.
而分割线的高度是 -1
Great. Now, we associate this model with the weights two,
很好 现在我们在这个模型中得到了
minus four, one, and minus one.
权重 2 -4 1 和 -1
And now, the question is how do we find this weight.
现在问题是 我们如何确定权重
Well, here's a way to do it. Here are three mountings or functions.
有一个方法 这里有三座山 或者说是三个函数
One on top of each point.
每个点上都有一个
Now, under each point,
现在 在每个点下面
let's record the value of the function at every point,
我们来记录这个点的三个函数值
so literally, how tall is the mountain at that point?
也就是在这一点上 每座山有多高
For the first point, we have that the green mountain has a height one,
在第一个点上 绿色山的高度为 1
since we constructed the mountain precisely to peak at that point.
因为我们故意把这座山的顶峰画在了在这一点上
The other two heights that are small.
另外两个高度比较小
Since the yellow one, the brown mountains are pretty low at this point.
黄色和棕色的山在这个点上相对比较低
So let's say, there are 0.08 And 0.02.
分别是 0.08 和 0.02
Then we do the same thing with the second point and with the third point.
我们在第二和第三个点也这么做
Notice that each point will have one value of one on their vector of heights,
注意每个点都的高度矢量中都有一个数值为 1
since the height of the mountain corresponding to that point is one by construction.
因为我们在每个点上构建的山脉峰值就是 1
In general, the other values will be small but we may have some close
总体来说 其他值比较小 但可能有些相近点
by points that will give us high values. This doesn't matter.
也会带来高值 这不重要
Now the question is,
现在问题是
how do we find the right linear combination of green, yellow,
如何寻找正确的绿、黄、棕色山脉函数的线性组合
and brown functions which will be able to separate the blue and the red points?
从而分开蓝点和红点呢？
Well, here's where the magic happens.
现在是见证奇迹的时候了
Let's take this three height vectors and just plot them in
我们把这三个高度矢量绘制在
a three dimensional space. Here they are.
一个三维空间里 就像这样
Notice that they're very close to being the three basis vectors,
注意它们非常接近于三个基向量
since they have a one in each of the coordinates and almost zero on the other two.
因为它们的坐标里都有 1 另两个数值都接近 0
As I stated before,
正如我开头所说
this isn't always the case,
情况不是永远都这样
but this doesn't matter as long as it gives us a set of points that we can separate.
但是没关系 只要它能使我们分开这些点就行
And since we have as many dimensions as points,
鉴于我们有三个点以及三个维度
then this space is very highly dimensional,
且这个空间是高维度空间
so chances are we'll be able to separate our points well.
因此我们很有可能能分开这些点
So, with some luck in the application of our known SVM algorithm,
所以 运用我们已经学过的 SVM 算法
let's say we're able to separate these red and blue points with this plane over here.
我们可以用这个水平面来分开这些红点和蓝点
A plane with equation say, 2x - 4y + 1z = -1.
假设水平面的方程是 2x-4y+1z=-1
So, let's remember this equation.
我们要记住这个方程
This is going to be a useful equation.
这个方程很有用
And the reason it's useful is the following.
因为它在接下来会发挥很大的作用
If we take the constants of the equation off the plane,
如果我们把这个水平面方程的常数拿下来
then they become the constants of our model,
就成了我们模型的常数了
namely our mountain range consist of finding two times this mountain
也就是两倍的这座山脉
minus four times this other one plus one times this other one.
减去四倍的这座山 再加上一倍这座山
And the line that separates this points,
而分开这些点的这条线高度等于 -1
the line at height minus one for the constant term. Magic.
也就是方程中的常数 -1 神奇吧